3 2 live.
>> I say welcome brothers and sisters to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother Tazadaq.
>> And God spake all these words saying,
I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of any anything
that is in heaven above, or that is in
the earth beneath, or that is in the
water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy.
Six days shalt thou labor, and do all
thy work.
But the seventh day is the sabbath of
the Lord thy God.
In it thou shalt not do any work, thou,
nor thy son, nor thy daughter, nor thy
man servant, nor thy maid servant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates. For in six days the
Lord made heaven and earth, the sea, and
all that in them is, and rested the
seventh day. Wherefore the Lord blessed
the sabbath day, and hallowed it. Honor
thy father and thy mother, that thy days
may be long upon the land which the Lord
thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house.
wife, nor his man servant, nor his maid
servant, nor his ox, no his ass, nor
anything that is thy neighbor's.
We read Exodus 20:1-17, and may the Lord
have a blessing to the reading of his
words. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
So, in question and answer, you can ask
us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate, we're here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also,
remember that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you keep them to or two scripture
maximum. But, let me introduce to you
the family that's on the panel this
evening. We got brother Jerome.
>> Grace and peace.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening, everybody.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Tanzeel.
>> Uh sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> And we have sister Casey with us as well
as a guest caller. And I'm brother
Cornell. Uh sister Deborah, before we
get started with our first question, I
just wanted to remind everybody that um
that tomorrow at evening will be the
second Passover. If you cannot take part
in the first Passover, according to the
Lord God, which was on Wednesday, April
the 1st, then the second one will be
April the 30th at sundown. And with that
being said, sister Deborah, now, what is
our first question of the evening?
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So,
uh Stacy Jones asked, "Is it unlawful to
divorce your wife for unbelief?"
>> All right, if your wife is part of
unbelief, is it lawful unlawful to
divorce her?
Brother Dre.
>> Let's [clears throat] go to Matthew 19.
We had a similar question
to this last week. So, we going to
reference
Matthew 19
and uh
read verse three and skip to nine.
When you get it, Tanzael, go ahead and
read it.
>> The Pharisees also came unto him
tempting him and saying unto him, "Is it
lawful for a man to put away his wife
for every cause?"
>> Mhm.
Verse nine.
>> And I say unto you, "Whosoever shall put
away his wife, except it be for
fornication, and shall marry another,
committeth adultery. And whoso marry her
which is put away, do commit adultery."
>> So, unbelief is not right there.
So, let's go over to 1 Corinthians 7.
1 Corinthians 7
and pick it up at verse 10.
When you get there, read that 1
Corinthians 7 and 10.
>> And unto the married I command, yet not
I, but the Lord, "Let not the wife
depart from her husband.
>> Mhm.
>> But and if she depart, let her remain
unmarried or be reconciled to her
husband. And let not the husband put
away his wife."
>> So, let not the husband put away his
wife. And if the wife depart, let her
remain unmarried or be reconciled to her
husband. Verse 12.
Go ahead.
>> But to the rest speak I, not the Lord.
If any brother have a wife that
believeth not, and she be pleased to
dwell with him, let him not put her
away.
>> So, you got an unbelieving wife, and she
be pleased to dwell with you, don't put
her away.
Verse 14. Go ahead.
>> For the unbelieving husband is
sanctified by the wife.
And the unbelieving wife is sanctified
by the husband.
Else were your children unclean, but now
are they holy.
>> So, [clears throat] what we see here,
whether it be the wife or the husband,
the unbelieving
one is sanctified
by their mate,
and your children are covered in that
sense. But, let's look at something
else. Let's go to Ephesians 5.
And and consider this, if the Lord
left us alone,
where would we be right now?
Ephesians 5:25
and 26.
Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
>> [clears throat]
>> Husbands, love your wives,
even as Christ also loved the church,
and gave himself for it,
that he might sanctify and cleanse it
with the washing of water
by the word.
>> So, the Lord
is we we told to love our wives like
Christ loved the church, and gave
himself for it, that he might sanctify
and cleanse it with the washing of the
water by the word. And we,
if we are there with our unbelieving
mate,
and they be pleased to dwell with us, we
shouldn't put them away, because
they are sanctified
in that sense. And who knows whether
they might turn back and serve God or
not.
But go ahead. Read Read a little bit
more.
>> That he might present it to himself a
glorious church,
not having spot or wrinkle, or any such
thing, but that it should be holy and
without blemish.
So, are
>> Go ahead.
>> So, are men to love their wives as their
own bodies.
He that loveth his wife loveth himself.
For no man ever yet hated his own flesh,
but nourisheth and cherisheth it, even
as the Lord the church.
For we are the members of
>> Okay, that's good enough.
No, don't leave your wife if she's not
believing.
>> Right.
>> Divorce her. No.
That's all I got.
>> Right.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answer their question. Next
question.
>> Next one. Linda Stringer says in Acts
19:9,
it says that Paul left the synagogue and
started teaching in the school of
Tyrannus.
I read that the school of Tyrannus was
an Ephesians school where the Greek gods
and philosophy were taught. Are there
any books out there where Hebrew
Israelites
in Jesus' time wrote any New Testament
testimony besides the letters of Paul?
>> All right, brother Julius.
Let's go to that scripture and read it,
uh,
Brother Kanzel. Acts 19. This time,
let's pick this up at verse 8. Let's
pick up what Paul was doing cuz all Paul
did was preach and evangelize the gospel
of the kingdom of God
Uh, uh to the Gentiles among among the
Gentiles. Go ahead at verse eight.
>> And he went to the synagogue and spake
boldly for the space of three months,
disputing and persuading the things
concerning the kingdom of God.
>> Uh-huh.
>> But when the divers
>> things concerning the kingdom of God.
Go ahead.
>> But when divers were hardened and
believed not, but spake evil of that way
before the multitude, he departed from
them
and separated the disciples, disputing
daily in the school of one Tyrannus.
>> One more verse.
>> And this continued by the space of two
years,
so that all they which dwelt in Asia
heard the word of the Lord Jesus,
both Jews and Greeks.
>> So now,
uh
it doesn't matter what school of
Tyrannus or where it was,
Paul didn't practice paganism. Paul
preached the gospel everywhere he went,
and he was
uh
uh people came up on him and people
approached him. People didn't agree with
him. The Jews didn't agree with him,
some of them, and some of the Gentiles
didn't agree with them. So it doesn't
matter what was being taught. What
better place to start teaching than in
the school of paganism?
And when you put the gospel out to the
people, so therefore, that's why I want
him to read that 10th verse.
And it said that he continued by the
space of two years, so that all which
dwelt in Asia heard the word of the Lord
Jesus, both Jews and Greeks.
So,
even though he was in a pagan country,
uh teaching uh
uh uh uh
dealing with people practicing other
gods and all that kind of stuff, has
nothing to do with what Paul was doing.
And the second part of your question is
uh
any Hebrew Israelites that wrote, like
Luke and Matthew and Mark them, they all
did it after the death and resurrection
of Jesus because they were living the
New Testament. So, I wouldn't even look
for other books that's
that's prior to that.
Because all we going to do is get
ourselves in trouble.
Let's just stick with the books that are
written. They are historical and they
are biblical and they are backed by
history.
That's all I got, Cornell.
>> Yes, sir. The 66 books are truly enough.
All right, brother. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered their question as we
continue to move on to our next one.
>> Next one, Valencia wants you to explain
Romans 3 verses 7 and 8.
>> Let's go to that Romans 3.
And read that verse 7 and 8 and the
guest caller will take it from there.
>> Romans 3 7
and 8.
For if the truth of God have more abound
through my lie unto his glory,
why yet am I also judged as a sinner?
And not rather, as we be slanderously
report and as some affirm that we say,
"Let us do evil that good may come."
whose damnation is just.
>> Okay, that's
that's simply saying that the word of
God and his truth is not
predicated
on
what we believe or what we say.
If the word of God is true at all times,
whether we believe it or whether we
don't or whether somebody lie
on it,
it still don't change nothing. Let's
back up to uh
verse uh uh
back up to Romans 3
and start out reading. We going to read
from 1 to uh uh
1 to 4
first. Go ahead.
When you get there.
>> What advantage is there in having the
Jew?
Or what prophet is there of
circumcision?
With much every way, chiefly
because that unto them were committed
the oracles of God.
For what if some did not believe? Shall
their unbelief make the faith of God
without effect?
God
>> What he's saying
What he's saying here is that
Israel have an advantage because the
word of God was committed in our hand.
But uh
what if you have some
that don't believe?
Do that make the truth of God uh uh uh
to have no no effect?
What's it say? Read verse 4.
>> God forbid.
But yeah, let God be true. But every man
a liar. As it is written,
that thou mightest be justified in thy
saying, and mightest overcome when thou
art judged.
>> So the whole thing is the word of God is
not established on what somebody believe
or disbelieve.
Whether somebody uh uh uh
think it's wrong or think it's right.
The word of God is always perfect.
And you cannot make the word uh uh
enhance the word of God by lying to make
it look good.
It's simply saying.
If somebody don't believe it,
that's on them. The word of God is
established
on its own. It stand by itself. It need
no support from nobody else. All it need
to be done is read the way it is.
So whether you believe believe the word
of God or whether you
speak against it
or speak
for it,
it don't need our testimony. It stands
by itself. That's all it's saying. You
don't have to say.
>> All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next question.
>> Uh next one, Shavonda asks, "Is it
considered dishonoring our parents when
speaking of them in our testimony
or when talking to my children about
certain circumstances
pertaining to my deceased parents and
when giving advice?"
>> All right. So, is it considered
dishonoring our parents when speaking of
them in our testimony? Let's open this
up to the panel.
>> Well, no.
What it's saying is this is a
when you
what it's saying in in
Exodus the 20th 20th chapter, honor your
mother and your father, that's talking
about your reaction with them, not about
them after they have died.
It's the way you treat them, the way you
address them.
Let's go in Leviticus
20th chapter and read verse nine.
And see and
and
go ahead.
>> That was Leviticus 20 verse nine?
>> Yep.
>> For everyone that curseth his father or
his mother shall be surely put to death.
He have cursed his father or his mother,
his blood shall be upon him.
>> Okay. Now, that's that's your reaction
to your parents, your disrespect.
Read 20 Exodus 21 and 17.
>> Yes, sir.
Exodus 21 and 17.
And he that curseth his father or his
mother shall surely be put to death.
>> This this is this is talking about what
you how you react
with your father or your mother or your
parent
while they are living.
Now let's go to one last place. Let's go
into Matthew
15th chapter and we're going to read
verses 1 through 6.
>> All right.
>> Go ahead when you get there.
>> Then came to Jesus scribes and Pharisees
which were of Jerusalem saying
Why do thy disciples transgress
transgress the tradition of the elders?
For they wash not their hands when they
eat bread.
But he answered and said unto them
Why do you also transgress the
commandments of God by your tradition?
For God commanded saying, "Honor thy
father and mother.
And he that curses father or mother let
him die the death.
But you say Whosoever shall say to his
father or his mother, "It is a gift by
whatsoever thou mightest be profited by
me.
And honor not his father or his mother
he shall be free.
Thus have you made the commandments of
God of none effect by your tradition.
>> Now what it's saying there Jesus said,
"Look going to tell you honor your
mother and your father. Yeah, but if
anything that you you get from you
like if you help them out, give them
money, whatever and
uh uh they don't have to pay it back
then you don't have to honor them
because you're giving them money and and
and and and and other stuff. He said,
"But that's got to be but that make the
word of God have no effect to honor your
mother and your father. There ain't no
conditions under that.
If you're taking care of
if they uh get sick and you have to
bring them into your house.
Uh if you have to pay their medical
bills or buy them groceries, they still
your mother and your father. Yes. And
you don't have the right to
talk down to them, to holler at them,
to
talk ugly or curse them.
You honor them like the Lord said.
Even if they dishonor you.
That's between them and God.
When you reciprocate by talking crazy or
hollering at them or
pushing them or doing anything negative
to them, that's between you and God.
It ain't got nothing to do with what
what you say after they are dead. It's
how you treat them while they are
living.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Uh next one. Mo' Money
Waters says, "I'm confused.
The other Bible study,
you guys told me that we should never
pray to God, but to the Father in Jesus'
name. But I don't understand because of
these verses.
Philippians 4
verses 6 and 7 and Psalms 54 verse 2."
>> All right. So, Mo' Money Waters uh
fixing that confusion is on the way.
Brother Jerome.
>> Uh let's go read that
uh those verses. Philippians
4 6 and 7.
>> Philippians 4 6 and 7.
Be careful for nothing, but in
everything by prayer and supplication
with thanksgiving, let your request be
made known unto God.
And the peace of God was passed of all
understanding shall keep your hearts and
mind through Christ Jesus.
>> And and and the uh
Psalms 54:2.
>> Psalms 54:2.
>> You get it. Go ahead.
>> Hear my prayer, oh God.
Give ear to the words of my mouth.
>> Okay. So,
uh in dealing with both those verses
that you gave, you you you you you
actually pray to the Father.
All right? In the name that the Father
gave to the Son, which is Jesus.
You know, cuz the Father gave him his
name.
Okay? We learn that in Philippians,
okay? The second chapter. All right? So,
uh let's go to that Philippians 2 and
we're going to read verse 9 through 11.
Philippians 2, verse 9 through 11.
You get it. Go ahead and read.
>> Wherefore God also have highly exalted
him.
And given him a name which is above
every name.
That at the name of Jesus
every knee shall bow
of things in heaven and things in earth
and things under the earth.
And that every tongue shall confess that
Jesus Christ is Lord for the glory of
God the Father.
>> Yeah, to the glory of God the Father.
Let's go to Saint John chapter 5
and read verse 43.
>> Saint John 5:43.
I am come in my father's name and you
receive me not.
And if another shall come in his own
name, him you will receive.
>> Yeah, so Jesus telling you he said I
came in my father's name. I didn't come
in my own name.
Okay? The father's name is actually
Jesus. All right? And so we pray to the
Father in the name that the Father gave
to the Son, which is Jesus. Okay? One
more place and I'll be done. Matthew's
chapter 6 verse 9. He tell us to pray to
the Father.
And we know to pray to the Father in the
name that the Father gave the Son as
Jesus.
Matthew 6 and 9.
>> After this matter therefore pray
Our Father which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
>> Hallowed be thy name. The Father's name
is hallowed.
>> Right.
>> That's all I got and that name is Jesus.
>> All right, thank you for that.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next question.
>> Uh next one, Shavonda says my oldest
daughter which is 13 asked, "When a
person becomes the age of accountability
for sins, do they still reap what
they've sown as a child?"
>> All right. We're talking about a
daughter here and accountability.
Brother Dre, what you say?
>> It's good that your 13-year-old daughter
got a mind
to have accountability in her heart. But
let's go to 1 John the first chapter.
1 John the first chapter and we going to
read
verses 8 and 9.
Go ahead when you get there, Tenzel.
>> If we confess our sins, he is faithful
and just to forgive us our sins
and to cleanse us from all
unrighteousness.
>> Okay, now read verse 8.
>> If we say that we have no sin, we
deceive ourselves and the truth is not
in us.
>> That's right. So, you know, the
scripture says all have sinned,
but
if we confess our sins, he is faithful
and just to forgive us our sins and to
cleanse us from all unrighteousness.
>> Right.
>> Let's go to
uh 1 Corinthians 13.
1 Corinthians 13
and
let's look at verse 11.
This is what Paul said here.
1 Corinthians 13 and 11. Go ahead.
>> When I was a child,
I spake as a child. I understood as a
child.
I thought as a child.
When I became a man,
I put away childish things.
>> The good thing is your 13-year-old
is thinking
what would be pleasing to the Lord and
she don't want to displease the Lord.
So, that's a good thing.
But because uh the scripture tell us uh
in Proverbs 22 and 15, the foolishness
is bound in the heart of a child, but
the rod of correction will drive it far
from them. Let's go to the last place.
Let's go to Ezekiel 18.
Ezekiel 18
and read verses 20 to 22.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
>> The soul that sinneth, it shall die.
The son shall not bear the iniquity of
the father, neither shall the father
bear the iniquity of the son.
The righteous
The righteousness of the righteous shall
be upon him,
and the wickedness of the wicked shall
be upon him.
>> Mhm.
>> But if the wicked will turn from all his
sins that he have committed and keep all
my statutes and do that which is lawful
and right,
he shall surely live, he shall not die.
>> Go ahead.
>> All his transgressions that he have
committed, they shall not be mentioned
unto him and his righteousness that he
have done, and he shall live.
>> One more verse, verse 23. That's it.
>> Have I any pleasure at all that the
wicked should die? Sayeth the Lord God.
And not that he should return from his
ways and live.
>> So the Lord wants us if we have sin in
our youth
is to repent.
Whether it be we young or old. You know,
one thing that David said in Psalm 25,
David prayed to God and he asked the
Lord to not remember the sins of his
youth.
In Proverbs 25 and 7.
So it's a good mind to have that mindset
at 13. And and I pray that you continue
with it. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
And
we wish the walker, that 13-year-old,
the best. All right.
Let's move on to our next question.
>> Uh yes, here's another question on
honoring your mother and father from
More Muddy Waters. What is classified as
not honoring thy mother and thy father
and is talking back dishonoring them or
correcting them if they get something
wrong?
>> All right, classification
as not honoring thy mother and thy
father. Brother Julius.
>> The guest caller gave you some wonderful
examples of of dishonoring your mother
and your father. The
Let's go to Exodus the 21st chapter. Go
back and listen to his answer again.
Exodus the 21st chapter.
Because
it dishonor your mother, your father
covers a lot of things. Your your verbal
your the and um
Let the Bible speak.
If putting you pushing them and hitting
them. Exodus Exodus 21 and read verse
15, Tenzel.
>> And he that smiteth his father or his
mother shall surely be put to death.
>> So now you don't push them, you don't
hit them.
Verse 17.
>> And he that curseth his father or his
mother shall surely be put to death.
>> Now you Now you don't graduate from that
to cursing them out.
The Lord told you in 1 Corinthians the
14th chapter and verse 40 to do all
things decent and in order. How are you
talking? So you could correct your your
parents, but you do it in the spirit of
love, in the spirit of meekness,
understanding that they are still your
mother and your father.
So if you But if there going to be any
kind of correction, you do it with the
right kind of spirit and with the right
kind of tone. Remember, they are still
your mother and your father. The Lord
said, "Honor thy mother and thy father
that thy days be long." Didn't say if
they are drug abuser or if they are
alcoholic, you honor them because they
are your mother and your father.
And another way of not honoring them, my
last place, Romans the 13th chapter.
The Lord give you room. Even
you could be angry, but you don't sin
not.
Romans 13 and just verse one, Tenzel.
Romans 13 and one, what the book say?
>> Let every soul be subject unto the
higher powers.
>> Uh-huh.
>> There is no power but of God.
>> So, now
your mother and your father
because you in their house, they're
higher power. They took care of you when
you couldn't take care of yourself.
So, you submit yourself.
But when you don't submit yourself, I
ain't going to do nothing. I don't care.
I'm not doing nothing. And your mother
and father take the garbage out. You
won't be being disobedient. That's
another dishonor. So, it covers a whole
lot of things. So, let's let's do it
God's way.
So, you can be blessed. That's all I
got.
>> All right. Brother Jerome.
>> Yeah, hopefully you was tuned in when
you heard the guest calls.
Callers answer regardless regarding
honoring your mother and your father and
what it means to dishonor
you know, and what Julius just said. I'm
just going to add one thing. Let's go to
Leviticus 19:18.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Leviticus 19
You get it, go ahead and read.
>> And thou shalt not avenge nor bear any
grudge against the children of thy
people.
But thou shalt love thy neighbor as
thyself. I am the Lord.
>> So, one way another way to honor your
mother and your father is
treat them the way you want to be
treated.
And that's what the commandments is all
about.
Yeah.
That's all I want to add.
>> Yeah, cuz sometimes too, you reap what
you sow. How you treat your parents may
be how your children turn around and
treat you.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one, Stephen Googers asked, "Where
in the book of Jeremiah is it written
that Jesus was betrayed for 30 pieces of
silver? I know it's in Zechariah
11:12-13,
but this verse, Matthew 27:9,
refers to Jeremiah.
Where is it written?"
>> All right, brother Dre, what you say?
Let's go to Matthew 27:9.
And you asked the question
twice, Steven.
And the And the script you asked, "Where
is it written?"
And you said you know about Matthew
27:9,
but let's see if it says that it is
written
in Jeremiah in Matthew 27:9.
Read that, brother Tanzil.
>> Then was fulfilled that which was spoken
by Jeremiah the prophet, saying, "And
they took the 30 pieces of silver, the
price of him that was valued, whom they
of the children of Israel did value."
>> So, it it didn't say it was written, it
says it was spoken by Jeremiah the
prophet, didn't it?
Didn't say it was written by Jeremiah
the prophet. So, you asked the question
twice,
but it says it was spoken by him.
And you understand that it is written in
Zechariah 11.
Let's just go read that one more time,
Zechariah 11:12-13.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
>> And I said unto them, "If you think
good, give me my price. And if not,
forbear." So, they weighed for my price
30 pieces of silver.
>> Mhm.
>> And the Lord said unto me, "Cast it unto
the potter, a goodly price that I was
priced
at at at of them. And I took the 30
pieces of silver and cast them to the
potter in the house of the Lord."
>> Now, this is where this is written at.
But it was spoken in Jeremiah I mean,
when you it was spoken in Matthew it's
quoted Jeremiah that it was spoken
there.
So, it's not saying that it is written
in Jeremiah.
So, no, it's not written in Jeremiah.
That's all I got.
>> All right.
Thank you for that, brothers. We
continue to move on to our next
question.
>> Uh yes, next one. Nick Cloud asks for
you to explain Matthew 3:11.
The part where it says "baptized with
the Holy Ghost and with fire."
>> All right. Let's go to that.
Matthew 3.
Matthew the third chapter.
And let's pick it up at that verse 11.
Matthew
3.
Let's pick it up, brother first. Uh pick
it up at that verse uh 8.
Where when you repent at. What did John
say? Go ahead.
>> Bring forth therefore fruits meet for
repentance.
>> Yep. When you repent bring forth some
works to show that you are truly sorry.
Skip down to verse uh 11. Go ahead.
>> I indeed baptize you with water unto
repentance.
But he that cometh after me is mightier
than I.
Whose shoes I am not worthy to bear.
He shall baptize you with the Holy Ghost
and with fire.
>> Yes, baptize you with the Holy Ghost and
with fire. Let's first go and deal with
the Holy Ghost in John 16.
John 16.
When you get there, brother,
pick it up
at that verse
five, and then let's skip down. John 16
and five. Go ahead.
>> But now I go my way to him that sent me.
And none of you ask me whether goest
thou.
>> So, Jesus saying he going back to where
he came
before he came and died for the sins of
the world. Skip down to 13 and 14. This
Holy Ghost here, we talking about an
angel. Go ahead.
>> Howbeit, when he, the spirit of truth,
is come,
he will guide you into all truth.
For he shall not speak of himself,
but whatsoever he shall hear, that shall
he speak.
And he will show you things to come.
>> Yeah.
>> He shall glorify me. For he shall
receive of mine,
and shall show it unto you.
>> Yep, so the spirit of truth. And
actually, when Peter was talking about
the Holy Ghost, when he said repent and
be baptized every one of you in the name
of Jesus Christ for the remission of
sins, and you shall receive the gift of
the Holy Ghost, which is we talking
about that angel there to lead and to
guide you into all truth.
Now, when you ask about that word fire
in that verse Matthew 3 and 11, we are
talking about the word here. Let's go to
Jeremiah 23. Jeremiah the 23rd chapter.
And when you get to that Jeremiah 23,
let's pick it up, brother, at that verse
29. Jeremiah 23
and 29. And let's see
what it was that the Lord said here
at of own mouth.
Go ahead.
>> Is not my word like as a fire, saith the
Lord,
and like a hammer that breaketh the rock
in pieces?
>> Yeah, so that that word of God is just
like a fire. And that Matthew you asked
about when it said fire, we talking
about that word. The Lord it say his
word is just like a fire. Now, let's go
to Jeremiah 20, last place. And let's
see what Jeremiah said
when he thought that everybody was going
to be willingly accepting his word.
And he got hit in the mouth and punished
for it and put in stocks. Let's see what
he said. Uh pick it up, brother, at that
verse seven.
>> O Lord,
thou hast deceived me,
and I was deceived.
Thou art stronger than I, and hast
prevailed. I am in derision daily. Every
one mocks me.
>> For the truth. Go ahead.
>> For since I spake, I cried out. I cried
violence and spoil. Because the word of
the Lord was made a reproach unto me,
and in derision daily.
>> Yep.
>> Then I said, I will not make mention of
him, nor speak any more in his name.
But his word was in my heart as a
burning fire shut up in my bones.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was weary with forbearing, and I
could not stay.
>> So, we see Jeremiah here talking about
that word. He said that word was shut up
in his bones just like fire. He tried to
hold back, but he couldn't. He had to
speak that word. So, when you ask about
that word fire, we are talking about the
word in that Matthew 3 and verse 11.
And that's all I got.
All right. Hope that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Time check for
the next one.
>> Uh yes, the time is 8:11.
Christine Coleman asks, "Can any man
preach what is Can any man preach that
is grafted or adopted into Israel since
they are technically Israel now? We can
read that is spiritual now and not
physical anymore. I always wonder about
this topic."
>> All right, well wonder no more. Next
caller, go ahead.
>> Well, the first thing here is not
spiritual now. It's always been
spiritual.
>> Mhm.
>> So, the word is God tell you that his
word is spirit and they are life.
Nothing has changed.
But, the whole thing is this whole thing
is if you become a spiritual Israelite,
can you teach? Let's look at Romans the
9th chapter and read verse 1 through 4.
>> All right. Romans 9, 1 through 4.
I say the truth in Christ, I lie not. My
conscience also bear me witness in the
Holy Ghost.
That I have great heaviness and
continual sorrow in my heart.
For I could wish that myself were a
curse from Christ for my brethren, my
kinsmen according to the flesh.
Who are Israelites.
>> Let me intervene here.
He said he would Could it be a curse for
his
his brothers and his kinsmen according
to the flesh? He ain't talking
spiritually, is he?
No.
>> No.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> Who are Israelites.
To whom pertaineth the adoption.
And the glory.
And the covenants.
And the giving of the law.
And the service of God.
And the promises.
>> So, this talking about Israel.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Now,
you might become spiritually Israel by
by teaching or by listening and
learning, but
we talking about who God's priests are.
This is This is what's really behind
this question. Go to Romans the 30th
chapter and read verses 1 and 2.
>> What advantage then have the Jew? Or
what profit is there of circumcision?
Much every way, chiefly, because that
unto them were committed the oracles of
God.
>> This is talking about physical Israel. I
didn't see none about spiritual right
there.
>> Right.
>> Do we understand
where all these uh
uh uh uh
non-Israelite spiritual but spiritual
uh uh people
are referenced in the Bible. So, let's
go to Isaiah the 43rd chapter.
>> Mhm.
>> We going to read three verses. Verse 1,
verse 10,
and verse 20.
>> Yep.
Now, right.
But now,
thus saith the Lord that created thee, O
Jacob,
and he that formed thee, O Israel,
fear not.
>> Now, he's talking Now, listen. He's
talking about physical Israel. Isn't
Isn't that correct?
>> That's right.
>> Go ahead.
>> Fear not, for I have redeemed thee.
I have called thee by thy name, and thou
art mine.
Verse 10.
>> Okay.
That's Israel. They called by the Lord's
name. Verse 10, read it.
>> Ye are my witnesses, saith the Lord,
and my servant whom I have chosen.
>> Who
>> Who is he talking about Israel?
Who is he talking about Israel witness?
>> Israel.
>> Israel? He talking about Israel.
>> Mhm.
>> You didn't read?
>> That you may know and believe me
and understand that I am he.
And before me
there was no God formed, neither shall
there be after me.
>> Mhm.
Verse 20.
>> The beasts of the field shall honor me,
the dragons and the owls. Because I give
water in to the wilderness
and rivers in the desert
to give drink to my people, my chosen.
>> Who is it?
>> This people have I formed for myself.
They shall show forth my praises.
>> He said um this people
have I chosen for myself. They shall
show forth my praises.
That's talking physical.
Now let's go into conversation with
Jesus with the woman at the well.
Saint John the fourth chapter 19 through
22.
>> The woman said unto him, "Sir, I
perceive that thou art a prophet.
And our fathers worshipped in this
mountain.
And ye say that in Jerusalem in this
place where men ought to worship."
Then Jesus said unto her,
"Woman, believe me, the hour cometh
when ye shall neither in this mountain
nor at Jerusalem worship the Father.
Ye worship ye know not what.
We know what we worship. For salvation
is of the Jews."
>> Mhm.
Now did it that spiritual Jew, too?
>> Nope.
>> Mhm. Nope.
>> about the physical people here. This is
Jesus talking.
>> Right.
>> He is talking about
a people that he chose to do this.
And that people
is Israel. Look, when he when he picked
his 12 apostles,
how many spiritual Israelites did he
pick?
>> [clears throat]
>> None.
>> Even when he wanted to send a
uh uh uh uh uh
uh uh uh
a uh apostle to the Gentiles,
who did he pick?
>> Paul.
>> Israel.
>> Is Paul
He picked Paul.
Now, Paul told So, now, Paul talked to
uh uh uh uh uh
uh uh uh uh uh uh uh all these Gentiles,
but then you had a Gentile who was
Cornelius.
>> Yes, sir.
>> The Lord sent an angel to him
and told him, "Go and get one Peter, and
he will tell you what to do."
>> That's right.
>> come he didn't get this Cornelius? Cuz
he said, "This man fears God with all
his house." Didn't that's what the book
said?
>> What the book said?
>> How come he Why didn't he get this man
that feared him with all his house
and make him a apostle to the Gentiles,
being he was a Gentile?
>> Wasn't the protocol.
>> that would break the protocol.
>> Yeah.
>> And people don't seem to understand
this, and we got evidence
of what would happen.
Paul taught all them Gentiles
all over uh uh Europe and Asia.
And when
Titus took Israel out in 70
uh uh AD,
and all the and all the teachers were
scattered all over the world,
what did the Gentiles teach us now?
Going to heaven.
People in the hell being barbecued by
Satan.
First day of the week, Sunday,
is the Christian Sabbath day.
Jesus died on Good Friday, rose Easter
morning, Easter Saturday morning. Jesus
born on the 25th day of December. Oh,
that's about sun worship.
How is it
that the Gentiles that didn't go into
captivity or get scattered by anybody
forgot
all of that good teaching that Paul gave
them?
They had to be spiritual Israelite
because Paul said they become a part of
the Commonwealth of Israel.
>> Yeah.
>> But there ain't no teachers.
The Lord tell you even in Isaiah 61st
chapter, when he bring everybody back,
he said Israel is still going to be
called to preach to God.
>> That's right.
>> So now,
I don't want to sound uh uh uh
angry, and I'm not. I don't want to
sound abrasive, and I'm not. But I want
to tell you something.
God picked Israel to teach the people,
and if you don't get it from us,
you ain't going to get it right.
If you do,
then and uh uh
then Jesus didn't know what he was
talking about when he told that woman
that salvation is of the Jews.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yeah.
That's right. Guys called even told us
that you only have I known about all the
families of the earth.
>> That's right.
>> Right there.
>> Amos 3.
>> Yeah.
>> That's it. So,
all right.
We hope that you were able to receive
that light as we continue to move on to
our next question.
>> Moving on,
um
Jackie Wells says, "Well,
there is a dead body in the house.
How do I get myself clean when I leave
from visiting my mother?
>> All right. Well, you said well, there's
a dead body in the house.
I'm not sure if you meant when there's a
dead body in the house. If you're
speaking about an urn, cuz I'm sure
you're not talking about a literal body.
But if someone happens to die while
you're in that house or you enter in
there, then you know, that's a different
story. But if you have an urn, how is it
that you get yourself clean when you
leave from visiting your mother?
Let's go to that Numbers the 19th
chapter. Numbers 19, Tenzel.
And so this is going to deal with 7 days
versus the evening. If you are in a
house or go to the cemetery or touch a
dead body or be somewhere where someone
has died, you are unclean for 7 days.
But if you go to see your mother and
we're talking about an urn and you don't
touch the urn, you just go to your
mother's house, then you are unclean
until the evening because mom's house is
continually unclean. But when you leave
there, you go home, take your shower,
change your clothes. But let's go to
that Numbers 19.
And let's see who set up this law,
brother, by picking it up at verse 1
first. Numbers 19 and 1.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses and Aaron,
saying,
>> All right. This is the Lord giving the
law to Moses and to Aaron, saying, Let's
skip down to that verse 14 and we're
going to skip again. Go ahead.
>> This is the law when a man dieth in the
tent,
all that come into the tent, and all
that is in the tent shall be unclean 7
days.
>> Right. So this is the law when a man
dies in a tent or in your house or
somewhere all they come into that house
or that tent shall be unclean for 7
days. Skip down to verse 16.
>> And whosoever touches one that is slain
with a sword in the open fields
or dead body
or bone of a man
or grave shall be unclean 7 days.
>> So, whosoever touches one that is slain
with a sword in the open fields or dead
body or the bone of a man or grave or if
you go to the cemetery, you shall be
unclean for 7 days. But, if we speaking
about an urn that you don't touch, skip
down to verse 22.
>> And whatsoever the unclean person
touches
shall be unclean.
And the soul that touches it shall be
unclean until evening.
>> So, if you go to your mom's house, we
speaking about an urn that's still
there,
then once you leave, you unclean when
you enter in, but when you leave, you go
home, you take your shower, and at that
evening, then you will be clean. But,
when you go visit your mom, then hey,
taking on uncleanness and you're not
unclean until the evening.
That's all I got.
All right. We hope that that answers
your question answers to Deborah. We
moving right along.
>> Yes, Lawanda says, "In 1 Peter 2:9,
it clearly states it clearly stated whom
God's royal priesthood is. In Isaiah
11:12,
it declares God's punishment for his
chosen people. So, how do you determine
who can teach if their parents are not
born in the US?
>> All right. Kind of spin off of the
teaching. Let's go to that
1 Peter 2
and pick it up at that verse 9 dealing
about the chosen generation, a royal
priesthood, and the guest caller will
take it from there.
>> All right. 1 Peter 2 and 9.
But, ye are a chosen generation, a royal
priesthood,
an holy nation, a peculiar people that
ye should show forth the praises of him
who have called you out of dark
darkness into his marvelous blessed
light.
>> You know
he is still talking about Israel
because because he said you are chosen
the priesthood.
>> Mhm.
>> them that when he brought them out of
Egypt.
It's all that simple.
All he's saying is that we are the
Israel is. I'm talking about physical
Israel.
>> Mhm.
>> And when it come to
uh uh
And that's And that's That's what I just
got through saying.
Just elaborate that little on that a
little bit more is that people get
uh
angry and people feel left out and
people feel like they slide in against
because when you say Israel are the
Lord's priests, where do the Bible say
that?
You need the protocol. It don't have
nothing to do with how you feel
or how close you might be
to a stranger or the strangers, how many
is among you.
God sent Israel to bring all of his
children back to him. Now, that includes
strangers and everybody. So, we are a
royal priesthood.
But as far as this
as far as
the rest of this
Isaiah 11 and 12, let's go look at it.
Don't look like punishment to me.
It look like something after the
punishment.
But we going to start reading at verse
11. Isaiah 11 and 11 and 12. So we
reading what we going in what time this
is. Go ahead and read.
>> And it shall come to pass in that day
that the Lord shall set his hand again
the second time to recover the remnant
of his people
which shall be left from Assyria
and from Egypt and from Pathros and from
Cush and from Elam and from Shinar and
from Hamath and from the islands of the
sea.
And he shall set
>> Verse 12.
>> And he shall set up an ensign for the
nations. He shall assemble the outcasts
of Israel and gather together the
dispersed of Judah from the four corners
of the earth.
>> So that's So that's not a curse there.
That's the time when the Lord is going
to recover Israel. It's all
simple.
And as far as
as far as
who know who they are in the other
nations other than the US, look, we got
people all over Israelites all over the
world know who they are.
And we are kind of like
among the last ones to catch up with.
It's just like you got the
Danaite in Ethiopia. They know that they
out of tribe of Dan. I don't know what
tribe I'm out of.
We got the Gadites.
That's
That's in Nigeria.
They
call They call themselves Igbos.
Then in South Africa,
you've got the Lemba,
which are the Levites. So, what make you
think that we in the United States are
the only one that know that they are
Israel?
People all over all Israelites all over
the world know who they are. All this is
saying is that look,
the Lord is going to the
for the Israelites when he start to
gather his people, the Lord is going to
be getting Israelites, some that don't
know that they Israelites
all over the world out of all nations,
bringing them back. But, that don't mean
that there's not somebody in that nation
that don't know who they are.
But, you got a lot of people that don't
know because they don't believe. Even
like in the United States.
You tell the average black person that
you are Hebrew Israelite, "Well, how do
you know?"
Because I read the scripture, and the
scripture say what's going to happen to
us is a sign.
But, the same thing the other people has
got it, too.
>> To identify.
>> All right.
To Isaiah 11, it's talking about
recovering of Israel.
>> All right.
>> And then you've got the
uh 1 John, it's talking about we are
royal priesthood like I just said.
And it have not changed. That's all I
got to say.
>> All right.
Hope that that helped you with your
question as we continue to move on to
our next one.
>> Uh next one, brother Otis asks, "What
scriptures explain Enoch is not in
heaven?"
>> All right. [clears throat]
He ain't there, brother Jerome.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh let's go to uh
Saint John chapter 5 um chapter 3, I
mean,
verse 13.
>> Saint John chapter 3.
>> Yeah, Saint John chapter 3, verse 13.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> And no man have ascended up to heaven,
but he that came down from heaven.
>> Yeah, that's what it said. Jesus Jesus
said no man has ascended up in the
heaven,
but he that came down. And Jesus was the
one that came down from heaven. And we
talking about where the heaven where God
dwell.
>> Right.
>> So, if you read 2 Corinthians the third
chapter, I mean, I'm I'm sorry, the 12th
chapter, verse 2,
it says that the Lord dwelled in the
third heaven. Ain't but three.
Okay?
So,
and it also talks about where he dwell,
there's a light that he had created. And
it talk about that light in Genesis. And
then So, now let's go to a place and
tell you where it's at. No man has seen
that light, nor can can approach into
that light.
That light that the Lord created in
Genesis. It didn't even shine all the
way down to the earth.
That's why he created the sun and the
moon for. This light is where the Lord
dwell, and there ain't no man been there
but but the Lord that came down from
there.
Okay? So, let's go to
1 Timothy chapter 6.
And we going to read verse 14 through
16.
>> 1 Timothy chapter 6.
>> Yep, verse 14 and 16.
>> [clears throat]
>> That thou keep this commandment without
spot, unrebukable until the praying of
our Lord Jesus Christ.
Which in his times he shall show who is
the blessed and only pontiff ponti-
continent, the kings of kings and lord
of lords.
Who only have immortality,
dwelling in the light which no man can
approach unto,
who no man have seen
nor can see.
To whom be honor and power everlasting.
Amen.
>> This is the reason why we know Enoch
ain't in that third heaven
where the Lord dwell
in that light which no man can approach
unto
or can see or have seen.
That's That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question,
sister Deborah. New territory?
>> Uh no, we're continuing on with
>> Oh, that's right.
>> Uh Joseph says,
"My question is about Genesis 47
verses 13 through 26.
I was reading and wondering, is this
passage a shadow of future events or is
there a deeper level of meaning
understanding
here that anyone may be aware of?
When I read it, I thought of how it's
written, there is a famine in the world
for the word of God. Do these events
somehow connect?"
>> All right. Seem to have quite a bit
going on with that question, but it
begins in Genesis 47.
Tanzel, Genesis 47.
And they requesting 13 through 26 and
the guest caller will take it from
there. Genesis 47 and begin at that
verse 13.
>> There was no bread in all the land, for
the famine was very sore. And the land
of Egypt and all the land of Canaan,
fainted by reason of the famine.
And Joseph gathered up all the money
that was found in the land of Egypt, and
in the land of Canaan, for the corn
which they bought. And Joseph brought
the money to Pharaoh's house.
And when the money failed in the land of
Egypt, and in the land of Canaan, all
the Egyptians came unto Joseph, and
said, "Give us bread. Why should we die
in the prison, for the money failed?"
And Joseph said, "Well, give me your
cattle, and I will give you
for your cattle if money fail."
And they brought the cattle unto Joseph,
and Joseph gave them bread in exchange
for horses, and for the flocks, and for
the cattle of the herbs, for the asses.
And he fed them with bread for all the
castle the cattle for that year.
And when that year was ended, they came
unto him the second second year, and
said unto him, "We will not hide it from
our lord. How that our money is spent,
my lord, also have our herbs of cattle.
There is not uh left in the sight of my
lord, but our bodies and our lands.
So, wherefore shall we die before thine
eyes, both we and our land? Buy us and
our land for bread, and we and our land
will be servants unto Pharaoh, and give
us seed that we may live and not die,
that the land be not desolate."
And Joseph bought all the men of Egypt
for Pharaoh, and for the Egyptians sold
every man his field, because the famine
prevailed over them. So, the land became
Pharaoh. And as for the people, he
removed them to cities from one end of
the borders of Egypt even to the other
end thereof. Only the land of the priest
bought he not. For the priest had a
portion assigned them of Pharaoh, and
did eat their portions, which Pharaoh
gave them. To wherefore they sold not
their lands.
Then Joseph said unto the people,
"Behold, I have bought you this day.
>> What verse?
>> I'm at 23.
It's from 13 to 26.
>> Well, you know, I can answer that
question right now.
That is for
that time only.
Yep.
Have no greater meaning.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Thank you for that. Sister Deborah, our
next question.
>> Uh yes, brother Anthony wants you to
share some light on Galatians 4:9-11.
Is Apostle Paul speaking to Gentiles
only?
Many use this scripture against
the Sabbath day and the observing of
days. Could you please explain what this
scripture is talking about?
>> All right, brother Jerome, share some
light on that Galatians 4
verses 9 through 11.
Let's go read it.
>> But now, after ye have known God, or
rather are known of God, how turn ye
again to the weak and beggarly elements,
whereunto ye desire again to be in
bondage? To observe days and months and
times and years. I'm afraid of you.
Lest I have bestowed upon you labor in
vain.
>> Okay.
Um
Uh as you can read, he was initially
talking to Galatians, but
the message is for
everybody that read it. It's for all the
nations.
Okay?
Uh and in regards to the Sabbath day, he
not speaking against the Sabbath day,
neither is that talking about it being
one of the uh
uh
observed days of uh uh times or it's
it's not talking about the Sabbath day
regards to that.
Okay? Uh the Sabbath day
the Lord said he is the Lord
of the Sabbath day.
Our Lord and Savior, okay?
And the Sabbath day is the seventh day
of the week. But uh let's go read uh
Matthew's 12 and then I'll come back. We
going to come back and and read this
again cuz we going to go to Deuteronomy,
okay, after that, okay?
>> Okay.
>> But I wanted to show that the Lord said
he the Lord of the Sabbath day. And
you know, and
Matthew's 12:8.
>> For the Son of Man is Lord, even of the
Sabbath day.
>> Yeah, so if he the Lord of the Sabbath
day, then he our Lord, we supposed to be
observing the Sabbath day.
>> Right.
>> Which we do, okay? Uh and Paul, he tell
you
he he it was his manner to keep the
Sabbath day. That was long after uh
Jesus had rose and went back to heaven.
So let's let's go to Acts the 18th
chapter. Read verse 1. Then we going to
skip.
Just want to prove that it's not talking
about the Sabbath day.
Okay?
Showing you what Paul doing himself.
>> Right.
>> Acts the 18th chapter verse 1.
>> After these things Paul departed from
Athens and came to Corinth.
>> Okay? Now skip down to verse 4.
>> And he reasoned in the synagogue every
Sabbath and persuaded the Jews and the
Greeks.
>> He persuaded the Jews and the Greeks.
Okay? Every Sabbath.
So he keeping it, sisters and brothers.
Now uh
go back to that Galatians 4 cuz I want
to do Deuteronomy
to address what he really talking about,
okay?
Go back to that uh
Galatians
4. Pick it up and just read verse 9 and
10.
>> But now, after that you have known God,
or rather unknown of God, how turn you
again to the weak and beggarly elements,
whereunto you desire again to be in
bondage?
You observe days and months and times
and years.
>> Yeah. So, now let me show you what he
really mean by that. Go to Deuteronomy
chapter 4.
>> Brother Jerome, before we go there, can
I intervene? Could we back up and read
verse 8?
Cuz Paul done preached to these people,
he done brought them into the word of
God, and showing them how to become
heirs and joint heirs with Christ. Pick
it up at verse 8 and read it.
This is the This This is the weak and
beggarly elements that you come out of,
that he delivered you from. Go ahead.
>> How be it then, when you knew not God,
you did service unto them which by
nature are no gods?
>> So, y'all practice paganism.
So, now, you practicing paganism
paganism.
And now, read verse 9.
>> But now, after that you have known God,
or rather are known of God, how turn you
again to the weak and beggarly elements,
whereunto you desire again to be in
bondage?
>> Because you As long as you ain't serving
to a living God, you serving Satan
devil. You serving the paganism. You
observing the pagan holidays. So, he
done showed you before you came into the
knowledge of the truth, you served these
weak You knew not God. You served these
beggarly elements. But now, that you
known of God, uh uh uh uh
uh uh
He done delivered you and brought you to
the truth of the gospel, and now you
turn back to weak and beggarly elements
which cannot profit you. This is what
Paul is saying.
>> Okay, and I I just want to piggyback on
that to support what you just said.
Uh let's go to Deuteronomy 4.
Pick it up at the verse uh 14 read to
the 19. And then we going to do chapter
18. It's going to use the same
terminology that we read in that uh
Galatians
uh
fourth chapter. It's going to use the
same terminology. Okay?
So, pick it up at verse 14 read to the
19.
>> And the Lord commanded me at that time
to teach you statutes and judgments,
that you might do them in the land
whither you go over to possess it.
But take you therefore a good heed unto
yourselves, for you saw no manner of
similitude on the day that the Lord
spake unto you in Horeb out of the midst
of the fire.
>> Mhm.
>> Lest you corrupt yourselves and make you
a graven image, similitude of any
figure, the likeness of male or female,
>> Cuz if you doing it like Julius said,
you dealing with paganism. Go ahead and
read.
>> the likeness of any beast that is on the
earth, the likeness of any winged fowl
that fly in the air,
>> Mhm.
>> likeness of anything that creepeth on
the ground,
>> Mhm.
>> the likeness of any fish that is in the
waters beneath the earth.
>> Go ahead.
>> And lest thou lift up thine eyes unto
heaven,
and when thou seest the sun and the moon
and the stars,
>> So, that's how you dealing with that as
though that's something that the Lord
wants you to do, you dealing with
paganism as Julius said. You dealing
with the S U N and some sun worship.
Go ahead and read.
>> even all the host of heaven,
>> Mhm.
>> shouldest be driven to worship them,
>> To worship them. You see what I'm
saying? Go ahead and read.
>> and serve them, which the Lord thy God
hath divided unto all nations under the
whole heaven.
>> All right. Now, let's tie it with the
18th chapter.
We're going to read verse 9 through 14.
Read it quickly as you can.
>> When thou art come into the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee, thou shall
not learn to do after the abomination of
those nations.
>> Of the nations. Come on.
>> There shall not be found among you
anyone that make of his son or daughter
to pass through the fire.
Or that uses divination or any observer
of times.
>> Observer of times. What are you talking
about? He ain't talking about the
Sabbath day. He talking about what
Julius was talking about, paganism and
what we just read a minute ago. Go ahead
and read.
>> Or an enchanter or a witch.
Or charmer or con- consulter or familiar
spirit.
>> Familiar spirit. Dealing with fallen
angels.
>> That's right.
>> Dealing with fallen angels. Go ahead.
>> Familiar spirit or wizard or a
necromancer.
For all that do these things are
abomination unto the Lord.
>> Mhm.
>> Because of these abominations the Lord
thy God do it drive them out from before
thee.
>> That's good enough. That's all I got to
do.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Some good light there.
Now, sister Deborah, new territory.
>> Yes, we are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, April the 29th, 2026.
Kenya Hayes asks, "Could you please
explain Acts 2 verse 38?
What is the gift of the Holy Ghost?
When and how will you receive it? And
can you receive the Holy Ghost without
being baptized in the name of Jesus?"
>> Let's go and pick it up in that Acts 2.
And let's pick it up at 36 and read down
to that 38 and then let's open it up to
the panel.
>> Therefore, let all the house of Israel
know assuredly
that God have made that same Jesus whom
you have crucified both Lord and Christ.
Now, when they heard this, they were
pricked in their hearts and said unto
Peter and to the rest of the apostles,
"The men and brethren, what shall we
do?"
Then Peter said unto them,
"Repent and be baptized, every one of
you,
in the name of Jesus Christ for the
remission of sins.
And you shall receive the gift
of the Holy Ghost."
>> Read the next verse, Tanza.
>> For the promise is unto you and to your
children and to all that are far off,
even as many as the Lord our God shall
call.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, so
>> So, what is the gift of the Holy Ghost
and when and how will you receive it?
That's the first question.
>> First thing is
Go to St. John the sixth chapter.
I read from verse uh uh uh
maybe from
45 to
54 first.
>> St. John 6
>> Mhm.
>> 45
It is written in the prophets, "They
shall be all taught of God. Every man
therefore they have heard and have
learned of the Father have come up unto
me.
>> Mhm.
>> Not that any man have seen the Father
save he which is of God, he have seen
the Father.
Verily, verily, verily I say unto you,
he that believeth on me
have everlasting life.
And I am that bread of life.
>> Go ahead.
>> Your father did eat manna in the
wilderness and are dead.
This is the bread which cometh down from
heaven.
That a man may eat thereof and not die.
I am the living bread which came down
from heaven. If any man eat this bread,
he shall live forever.
The bread that I will give is my flesh
which I will give for the life of the
world.
>> Now, go ahead.
>> The Jews therefore strove among
themselves saying, "How can this man
give us his flesh to eat?"
Then Jesus said unto them,
"Verily, verily, I say unto you, except
ye eat the flesh of the Son of man and
drink his blood, ye have no life in you.
Whoso eateth my flesh and drinketh my
blood, have eternal life. And I will
raise him up
at the last day."
>> Skip down to verse 60 and read it.
>> And when Jesus knew in himself that his
disciples murmured at it, he said unto
them,
>> Verse 60.
Verse 60.
>> 60. Many therefore of his disciples,
when they had heard this, said,
"This is a hard saying. Who can hear
it?"
And when Jesus knew in himself that his
disciples murmured at it, he said unto
them, "Doth this offend you?
What what? And if you shall see the Son
of man ascend up where he was before?
It is the spirit that quickeneth.
The flesh
profiteth nothing.
The words that I speak unto you,
they are spirit and they are life."
>> Then now,
a ghost is nothing but a,
a slang for the word spirit.
So, Jesus told them about using a
physical thing coming to eat his flesh
and drink his blood.
And people know they can't do that.
So, he said, "This is a hard saying." He
said, "Look, I'm not telling you to eat
my flesh and drink my blood physically.
I'm telling you to eat my word."
"For the words that I speak, they are
spirit and they are life." And skipping
down to verse
66 and continue.
>> From that time many of his disciples
went back and walked no more with him.
Then said Jesus unto the 12,
"Will you also go away?"
Then Simon Peter answered him, "Lord, to
whom shall we go?
Thou hast the words of eternal life."
>> So, so it's all about the word. So, the
Holy Ghost that fills you is the word of
God.
>> Right.
>> And when you
And
And you cannot deal with the word of God
without getting baptized.
>> Right.
>> When When you get baptized, then that's
when you start to understand the word of
God. That is the That is the Holy Ghost
that you're going to receive. And that
is enough. Though the word is the word
of eternal life.
So, you ain't going to get baptized
right away. You don't believe the word
of God.
>> Right.
>> First thing is you
You have got to believe
that if you that you need to get
baptized in the name of Jesus. Then And
all the And once you do that, then you
understand why.
And you just increase in the knowledge
of God and you come and increase that
in knowledge by the word of God. That's
all I have to say. Anybody got anything
else?
>> And
>> Yeah, like you said in that verse,
like you said in that verse 41, then
they that gladly received his word were
baptized.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Yeah, so
you want to receive that word and walk
in it with all your heart, hey, you got
knowledge coming that you never seen
before.
>> That's it.
>> All right.
Yes, sir.
Hope that answered your question there
as we continue to move on, Sister
Deborah. Time is a ticking.
>> Yeah, Shen Cola Cool Joby says, "I post
verses and scriptures online.
Sometimes adding notes to elaborate.
I see it as storytelling to help others
understand.
Is that the same as interpreting?
And if so, is that wrong?"
>> Let's open that up to the panel.
And
I would suggest that when you post, make
sure you fully understand what you are
posting. But open to the panel.
>> It's not interpretation as long as you
explain what you post with another
scripture.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
>> The Lord and let you know, you know,
that's why the Lord said,
you know, whom shall we turn
teach knowledge?
Those that are
drawn from the milk. We're going to
teach them line upon line, precept upon
precept, here a little and there a
little. So, when you
post a scripture up there
and uh
you have to post the understanding of
the scripture with another scripture. If
you're just putting something up there
to have something because it came out of
Bible, then you're wasting your time and
everybody else's time.
>> Right.
>> That's all I'll say.
>> All right, sister Deborah, next one.
>> Next one. Uh MC says, "I work with a man
who dress like a woman.
We talk about Jesus and his return. He
says he's ready.
Am I overstepping my boundaries talking
to him about his life?"
>> All right. Uh
Brother Julius, you retired and you
supposed to deal with some of that. What
you say?
>> I say you preach the gospel
to the person.
Preach the gospel.
>> Yeah.
>> And the gospel tells how a man should
behave, how a woman should behave.
Just preach the gospel.
And what did What did the Lord say about
the watchman?
Warn the people.
Somebody go read that.
>> All right.
>> book and verse?
>> Okay.
We all searching more for that.
>> Ezekiel 33.
>> Yep.
>> Oh.
>> Yep, that's it, brother. Ezekiel 33
around there, verse three, right?
Ezekiel
>> The Lord going to tell you what what you
going to do and you supposed to warn the
people. And if you don't, then they can
tell you what's going to happen to you.
Read it.
>> Uh want to pick it up at verse one?
>> Yeah, that's good, Tan.
>> And again, the word of the Lord came
unto me, saying, "Son of man, speak unto
the children of thy people and say unto
them,
when I bring the sword upon the land, if
the people of the land take a man of
their coast to set him for their
watchman,
if when he sees the sword come upon the
land, he blow up the trumpet and warn
the people.
Then was whoever heareth the sound of
the trumpet and take them not warning.
If the sword come
>> [clears throat]
>> and take him away, his blood shall be
upon his own head.
>> Get down to verse 7.
>> So thou, oh son of man, I have set thee
a watchman unto the house of Israel.
Therefore, thou shall hear the word at
my mouth and warn them warn them for me.
>> Go ahead.
>> When I say unto the wicked, "O wicked
man, thou shall surely die. If thou
doest not speak to warn the wicked from
his way,
that wicked man shall die in his
iniquity. But his blood will I require
at thy hand.
>> Verse 9, one more.
>> Nevertheless, if thou warn the wicked of
his way to turn from it,
if he do not turn from his way, he shall
die in his iniquity. But thou has
delivered thy soul.
>> So that's all you could do is warn the
people from God. You warn them with the
word of God. And
if they read it and don't take heed,
that's on them. You have delivered you.
>> Lord said a man should not
Man should not wear that
Lord said a man should not wear that
which pertains to a woman.
>> Right.
>> that simple.
So you tell him where he's wrong. If you
don't tell him, then God going to deal
with you.
It's all I have to say.
>> Muted.
>> To Deborah time check for our next
question. My apologies.
>> All right. This will be the last one.
It's A57.
Be alert us.
In Psalms 88 verse 3 and verse 5, is
this the lake of fire? Will God remember
them and will we recognize or remember
family or friends who end up in the lake
of fire?
Psalms 88 verse 3 and verse 5.
>> All right, let's pick it up there.
Tanzil.
>> For my soul is full of trouble. My life
draws nigh unto the grave.
Verse 5.
Free among the dead, like the slain that
lie up in the grave, whom thou
rememberest no more.
They are cut off from thy hand.
>> This ain't got no
>> So is this the lake of fire?
>> And
And what was the other part of that
question, too?
>> Will God remember them and will we
recognize or remember family or friends
who end up in the lake of fire?
>> All right. Well, the Lord said he got a
book of remembrance, so hey.
And uh guest call.
>> And what was the first part the first
verse that he read? This he read.
>> It was Psalms 88 verse 3 and verse 5.
>> That's what I was telling you
uh uh uh
That is Jesus talking about himself. You
understand?
He let you know that
what he's going through on on the on the
cross.
He said, "My soul is full of troubles
and and uh uh my life draweth nigh unto
the grave."
That ain't got nothing to do with the
lake of fire.
>> No, sir.
>> And you said eight.
>> Yes.
>> What was the next
>> Um
>> the
What was the next one?
>> No, it was three and five.
>> And and oh, and three.
Oh, and okay, and five.
Uh let me see.
Free among the dead,
like the slain that lie in the grave,
whom thou rememberest no more.
They are cut off
from thy hand. This is still Jesus
telling them what's going to happen.
As far as if are you going Do God know
who you Yeah, he know who you are. And
will we know?
Sure, we'll know everybody that we knew.
But one uh Look at that thing where uh
uh
uh uh where rich man and Lazarus.
>> Yep.
>> At Abraham. Weren't they talking to one
another?
>> Yep.
>> Did they know one another?
>> So, if you end up in the lake of fire,
anybody that you know, you still going
to know them.
Whether they
he was there or they are.
>> Yep.
All right.
>> That's all right.
>> Okay, Sister Deborah, time check.
>> Uh 9:00.
>> All right. It is now 9:00 and we have
ran out of time.
And we like to say if you submitted a
question and we never a chance to get to
it, please go and resubmit it. Sister
Deborah will take it, put it in
rotation, and we will deal with that
question
at the next session.
So, we like to say once again that if
you didn't have an opportunity for our
late comers who came on, if you never
opportunity to
in the Passover on Wednesday, April the
1st. The second Passover will be
tomorrow
after sundown.
So, that'll be the second Passover. But,
we like to say until we all come
together again, please be safe,
be blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as brother
Tanzael closes us out.
>> Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever. In Jesus' name we
pray.
Amen.